Wolfgang Köhler Papers 1862-1976 Mss.B.K815
American Philosophical Society
- Series I. Correspondence, 1919-1976; 2 lin. feet (Box 1-7)
  - Kersten, Wilhelm, 1931; 1 item
  - Kitzinger, Ernst, 1961-1962; 3 items
  - Klees, Fritz, 1964; 1 item
  - Klein, George S., 1952; 1 item
  - Klein, Jerry, 1959; 1 item
  - Kleine-Horst, Lothar, 1963; 1 item
  - Kleisinger, 1933; 1 item
  - Klemmt, Alfred, 1932; 1 item
  - Klix, F., 1965-1967; 5 items
  - Kluver, Heinrich, 1959-1960; 3 items
  - Knight, Rex, 1930; 1 item
  - Knott, Garland, 1962; 1 item
  - Koehler, Otto, 1957; 1 item
  - Koffka, Kurt, 1929-1931; 6 items
  - Koffka, Mira, 1962-1967; 25 items
  - Köhler, Ivo, 1960-1962; 8 items
  - Köhler, Martin, 1947; 1 item
  - Köhler, Wilhelm, 1932; 2 items
  - Köhler, Wolfgang. Notes, n.d.; 7 items
  - Köhler, Wolfgang to Bryn Mawr dean..., 1937; 1 item
  - Köhler, Wolfgang. The Card Trick, n.d.; 1 item
  - Koltun, Walter L., 1966; 1 item
  - Komroff, Manuel, 1928-1929; 2 items
  - Konig, Ernst, 1955; 1 item
  - Koralle., 1931; 3 items
  - Koseleff, Paul, 1958; 1 item
  - Kosswig, C., 1956; 1 item
  - Kraft, Georg, 1934-1935; 2 items
  - Krech, D., 1938-1962; 3 items
  - Kreezer, George, 1931; 1 item
  - Krueger, F., 1933; 1 item
  - La Baum, W., 1929; 1 item
  - Lachman, Sheldon J., 1956; 1 item
  - Lamm, Helmut, 1961; 2 items
  - Landauer, A. A., 1965; 1 item
  - Langfeld, Herbert, 1957; 1 item
  - Lashley, K. G., 1950; 2 items
  - Lawson, Chester A., 1957; 1 item
  - Leeper, Robert W., 1958-1964; 4 items
  - Leeper, Robert W. and Peter Madison, 1959; 1 item
  - Leibowitz, Herschel W., 1966; 1 item
  - Letter to _, 1924; 1 item
  - Letters to Dr. Köhler, 1932-1933; 4 items
    all are postcards
  - Lewin, Kurt, 1929-1933; 6 items
  - Lewin, Kurt and Gertrud, 1931; 1 item
    postcard
  - Lichtenberger, H., 1929; 2 items
  - Liebert, Arthur, 1931-1932; 3 items
  - Liebmann, Susanne, 1958; 1 item
  - Linksz, Arthur L., 1943-1945; 3 items
  - Lipmann, Otto, 1930-1963; 4 items
  - Liveright Publishing Corporation, 1927-1966; 10 items
  - Loeser, J. A., 1929-1931; 2 items
  - Luchins, A. S., 1959-1963; 12 items
  - Luria, Alexander R., 1932-1962; 8 items
  - Luyken, Richard, 1932; 3 items
  - Madison, P., 1960; 1 item
  - Maehr, Martin J., 1963; 1 item
  - Maier, Norman R. F., 1931-1932; 2 items
  - Maltzew, C., 1928-1932; 2 items
  - Mandelbaum, M. M., 1959-1965; 4 items
  - Mandler, Jean M., 1967; 1 item
  - Marbe, K., 1929-1965; 2 items
  - Massachusetts Institute of Technology, 1962-1965; 13 items
  - Matthaei, R., 1931; 1 item
  - McCollough, Mrs. Celeste, 1960; 2 items
  - McDougall, William, n.d.; 1 item
  - Mearns, David C., 1959-1967; 7 items
  - Meili, 1958-1967; 2 items
  - Metzger, Wolfgang, 1929-1967; 16 items
  - Meyerson, J., 1928-1930; 5 items
  - Michotte van den Berck, Albert, 1954-1964; 6 item
  - Mieser, 1928; 3 items
    probably Henri Pieron, not "Mieser."
  - Miscellany, 1945-1967; 3 items
  - Moe, Henry Allen, 1956-1961; 12 items
  - Montaner, Jose Carlos, 1930; 1 item
  - Morrison, Desmond, 1962; 1 item
  - Mountjoy, Paul T., 1963-1965; 5 items
  - Mowrer, O. H., 1960; 1 item
  - Muller, G. E., 1934; 3 item
  - Muller, Ilse, 1933-1967; 2 items
  - Muller, Ilse. "Versuch uber phanomenal optische Underchdringlichkeit", 1933; 1 item
  - Murchison, Carl, 1928-1931; 6 items
  - Murphy, James, 1930; 2 items
  - Myers, C. S., 1931-1932; 2 items
  - Nakajima, Shinshu, 1958-1960; 2 items
  - Nathan, Dr., 1960; 1 item
  - National Research Council, 1929-1930; 3 items
  - National Science Foundation, 1955-1967; 2 folders
    - Folder 1, 1955-1957; 24 items
    - Folder 2, 1957-1967; 57 items
  - Naturwissenschaften, 1930-1932; 4 items
  - Neff, William D., 1957-1962; 2 items
  - Nernst, W., 1933; 1 item
  - New York University positions, 1959-1960; 7 items
  - Newman, Edwin B., 1961-1967; 5 items
  - Newspaper clippings, 1925-1967; 2 folders
    - Folder 1, 1925; 26 items
    - Folder 2, 1958-1967; 10 items
  - Obonai, Torao, 1961-1962; 2 items
  - Odbert, Henry S.
    RESTRICTED
  - Odebrecht, Fritz, 1932; 2 items
  - Oka, Hidemiti, 1929; 1 item
  - On Germany, n.d.; 2 items
  - Oppenheimer, J. Robert, 1953-1965; 4 items
  - Padagogisch-Psychologisches Institut, Munich, 1931-1932; 13 items
  - Panofsky, Erwin, 1959; 1 item
  - Papas, Aris T., 1964-1965; 4 items
  - Pardel, T., 1963; 1 item
  - Parsons, H. M., 1963; 1 item
  - Pastore, Nicholas, 1963; 1 item
  - Pear, T. H., 1930; 1 item
  - Pearson, G. H. J., 1958; 1 item
  - Pell, Arthur, 1969; 1 item
  - Penguin Books, Ltd., 1956-1958; 8 items
  - Perry, Ralph Barton, 1928; 2 items
  - Peschi, Silvio, 1964; 1 item
  - Peters, Heins Wolfgang, 1932; 1 item
  - Peters, W., 1947; 1 item
  - Pfeiffer, Louise, 1961; 2 items
  - Philipps, Tracy, 1932; 1 item
  - Physical Society, London, 1932; 1 item
  - Physiologisches Institut der Universitat, Leipzig, 1930; 1 item
  - Pinneo, Lawrence R., 1959-1961; 9 items
  - Planck, Max, 1933-1934; 4 items
  - Prasad, Kali, 1949-1950; 2 items
  - Pratt, Carroll, 1929-1962; 8 items
  - Prentice, William, 1966; 1 item
  - Pressy, Sidney L., 1961; 1 item
  - Pribram, Karl H., 1953-1974; 25 items
    Contains items donated from Pribram through Mary Henle in 1989, as well as 3 letters between Henle and Pribram in 1974.
  - Princeton University Press, 1957-1972; 8 items
  - Psychologisches Institut der Universitat, Berlin, 1931; 1 item
  - Purdom, Luther, n.d.; 1 item
  - Rabinowitz, Herbert S., 1958; 1 item
  - Rado, Richard, 1932; 1 item
  - Rausch, Edwin, 1967; 1 item
  - Reichenbach, Hans, 1930-1931; 2 items
  - Reid, John W., 1959; 1 item
  - Reimer, Dietrich, 1928; 1 item
  - Rencurello, Antos C., 1965; 1 item
  - Requests for articles..., 1956-1967; 53 items
  - Restorff, H von, 1934; 1 item
  - Reviews, 1965-1972; 3 folders
    - Folder 1, 1965-1972; 20 items
    - Folder 2, 1972; 8 items
    - Folder 3, 1969-1972; 18 items
  - Rexroad, Carl N., 1930; 1 item
  - Richter, Hans, n.d.; 2 items
  - Rieser, Leonard, 1965; 1 item
  - Riezler, Kurt, 1930; 1 item
    Was under Frankfurt-am-Main. Universitat
  - Rignano, Eugenio, 1928; 1 item
  - Rivoire, Jeanne L., 1961; 1 item
  - Robert, Curt, 1929; 1 item
  - Rock, Irvin, 1959-1966; 7 items
  - Rogosin, H., 1963; 1 item
  - Rohm, 1931; 1 item
  - Rosenblith, Walter A., 1949; 1 item
  - Rosenhaupt, Hans, 1930; 1 item
  - Rowland, Vernon, 1960; 1 item
  - Rubin, Edgar, 1922; 1 item
  - Rupp, Hans, 1935; 1 item
  - Sabik, Vincent, 1963; 1 item
  - Sakuma, Kanae, 1929; 1 item
  - Sato, Koji, 1963; 2 items
  - Savery, Barnett, 1962; 1 item
  - Schering, Harald, 1929; 1 item
  - Schiller, Paul von, 1932; 1 item
  - Schlick, M., 1923; 1 item
  - Schlossberg, Sarah, 1965; 1 item
  - Schmidt, H., 1932; 2 items
  - Schmidt-Ott, F., 1933; 4 items
  - Schneider, Arthur, 1929-1931; 2 items
  - Schneirla, T. C., 1959-1962; 2 items
  - Schrodinger, Erwin, 1932; 4 items
  - Schrodinger, Erwin. "Zur Boltzmannschen Theorie des zweiten Hauptsatzes", n.d.; 1 item
    Handwritten manuscript copy of text
  - Scriven, Michael, 1959; 1 item
  - Seashore, Carl E., 1929; 3 items
  - Seeber, 1931; 2 items
  - Seeman, William, 1965; 1 item
  - Sein Tu, n.d.; 1 item
  - Seth, George, 1958; 1 item
  - Shane, Joseph B., 1960-1964; 2 items
  - Shapiro, Meyer, 1961; 3 items
  - Shockley, F. W., 1929; 1 item
  - Sickles, W. R., 1966; 3 items
  - Simon, Margarete, 1932; 1 item
  - Simons, Hans, 1928-1931; 4 items
  - Simpson, George Gaylord, 1973; 4 items
  - SIPRA, 1962; 1 item
  - Slochower, H., 1930; 1 item
  - Smith, Courtney, 1957; 1 item
  - Societa Editrice Universitaria, 1961-1963; 17 items
  - Sodhi, K. S., 1958-1960; 6 items
  - Sollner, Karl, 1929; 1 item
  - Solomon, Richard L., 1962; 2 items
  - Soskin, William F., 1956; 1 item
  - Speech outline Kant Society, n.d.; 1 item
  - Spiegelberg, Herbert, 1961-1966; 3 items
  - Spitz, Herman H., 1961-1965; 9 items
  - Spranger, Edouard, 1934; 2 items
  - Springer, Julius, Verlagsbuchhandlung, 1928-1931; 3 items
  - Springer-Verlag, 1967-1968; 5 items
  - Stadtler, Michael, 1967; 1 item
  - Stern, W., 1932; 2 items
  - Stockmayer, Walter H., 1966; 1 item
  - Strauss, Allan, 1960-1963; 2 items
  - Stromeyer, Charles, 1964-1967; 4 items
  - Stumpf, C., 1928-1933; 12 items
  - Swarthmore College, 1946-1970; 6 items
  - Swarthmore College, Introduction of Dr. Köhler, n.d.; 1 item
  - Talbot, Theodore, 1964-1965; 2 items
  - Tepas, Donald I., 1959; 2 items
  - Teuber, Hans Lukas, 1959-1965; 14 items
  - Thoms, H., 198; 2 items
  - Thorndike, Edward L., 1929; 1 item
  - Thorpe, W. H., 1950; 1 item
  - Thouless, Robert, 1930-1958; 3 items
  - Tracton, Horace C., 1954; 1 item
  - Tresselt, Margaret, 1966; 1 item
  - University of California Press, 1955; 2 items
  - University of Kansas. Psychology Department, 1957; 5 items
  - Unknown, 1929-1961; 7 items
  - Unknown (drafts), 10 items
  - Usmadze, Dmitri Tiflis, 1929; 2 items
  - Verlagsbuchhandlung Julius Springer (see also Springer, Julius...), 1921-1964; 24 items
  - Vierkandt, Alfred, 1930-1932; 4 items
  - Viking fund, 1949-1951; 7 items
  - Vogel, Georg, 1962; 2 items
  - Vogt, P., 1932; 1 item
  - Voigt, Gunther, n.d.; 1 item
  - Volborth, Georg, 1929; 1 item
  - Waldhausen, von, 1930; 1 item
  - Wallach, Hans, 1935-1965; 8 items
  - Wasserman, Jerry, 1961; 1 item
  - Watson, David, 1929; 1 item
  - Watson, Goodwin, 1930; 1 item
  - Wegener, Jonathan G., 1956-1957; 4 items
  - Weidlich, Karl, 1932; 1 item
  - Weisbach, W., 1928; 3 items
  - Weiskrantz, Lawrence, 1966; 2 items
  - Weiss, Paul, 1931; 1 item
  - Weissmann, S. J., 1924; 3 items
  - Wenner- Gren Foundation for Anthropological Research, 1951-1952; 5 items
  - Werner, Heinz, 1962; 1 item
  - Wertheimer, Max, 1929-1931; 13 items
  - Wertheimer, Michael, 1956-1958; 4 items
  - Wesleyan University, 1960; 1 item
  - Windelband, Dr., 1927-1931; 2 items
  - Wirtel, Thomas, 1967; 2 items
  - Wissenschaftliche Buchgesellschaft, 1961-1962; 2 items
  - Witte, Wilhelm, 1959-1967; 10 items
  - Wolin, Lee R., 1965; 1 item
  - Woods, 1926; 3 items
    were filed in the "Woods, Dorothy L." foler.
  - Woods, Dorothy, 1966; 7 items
  - Woodworth, Robert S., 1959; 1 item
  - Youniss, James, 1959-1960; 2 items
  - Zahn, Hans Eberhard, 1963; 1 item
  - Zangwill, Oliver L., 1932-1957; 3 items
  - Zener, Karl, 1960-1961; 2 item
  - Zimmermann, R., 1924; 1 item
  - Zunini, Giorgio, 1959; 2 items
  - Zweig, A., 1959; 1 item
  - Zyve, D. L., 1930; 1 item
- Series II. Grant Material, 1958-1967; .5 lin. feet (Box 1)
  The series is budgetary material related to grants Köhler received, and contain budget reports, receipts, check stubs for expenditures, and correspondence regarding payments.
  - Grant materials, subject receipts, n.d.; 17 items
  - Ford Foundation, 1959-1960, 13 items
  - National Science Foundation, no. 1725, 1956-1958; 18 items
  - National Science Foundation, no. G 5522, 1958-1962; 3 Folders
    - Folder 1, 1958-1961; 34 items
    - Folder 2, 1961; 43 items
    - Folder 3, 1962; 33 items
  - National Science Foundation, no. G 18635, 1963; 31 items
  - National Science Foundation, no. GB-2497., 1964-67; 4 folders
    - Folder 1, 1964; 37 items
    - Folder 2, 1965; 25 items
    - Folder 3, 1966; 16 items
    - Folder 4, 1967; 2 items
  - National Science Foundation, Reports, 1960-1967; 8 items
- Series III. Lectures, 1932-1969; 1.5 lin. feet (Box 1-4)
  Contains primarily manuscripts of lectures, and a few graphics where noted.
  - The Bad Mood in Science: Influences Responsible for it; No Reason for it to continue., n.d.; 3 items
    in German
  - Currents of the Human Auditory Cortex., n.d.; 1 item
    Chart
  - Currents of the Auditory Cortex in the Cat., n.d.; 2 items
  - Currents of the Visual Cortex in the Cat., n.d.; 2 items
    text and charts
  - Democracy and education, Colby College., 1 item
  - Die Entstehung von Leidenschaften., n.d.; 3 items
  - Figural After-effects., n.d.; 2 items
  - Figural After-Effects, by Köhler and Wallach. Manuscript for book, 1944; 3 folders
    - Folder 1, pp. 1-50, 1944; 1 item
    - Folder 2, pp. 51-100, 1944; 1 item
    - Folder 3, pp. 101-197, 1944; 1 item
  - Filene Conference, Dartmouth, 1962. "Role of psychology in the resolution of international conflict.", 23 items
  - Gestalt Psychology. Address for 1967 Convention of American Psychological Association., 3 items
  - Gestalt Psychology, Haverford, n.d.; 2 items
  - Gestalt Psychology, Origin and development., 4 items
  - Gestalt Psychology in memory, given at Dartmouth College., n.d.; 3 items
  - Gestalt Psychology in 1962., 6 items
  - Gestalt Psychology Today (ca. 1955?)., 5 items
  - Gestalt Psychology Today (1959)., 8 items
  - Gestaltpsychologie., n.d.; 4 items
  - Gestaltpsychologie und Hirnforschung., 2 items
  - Gifford Lecture
    - Acknowledgement of invitation: Announcement of lectures., 1958; 3 items
    - First course, 1958
      - No. 1. Neutral facts and factors., 1958; 3 items
      - No. 2. Scientism., 1958; 2 items
      - No. 3. Scientism and negativism., 1958; 4 items
      - No. 4. Value and sense., 1958; 5 items
      - No. 5. Sentiments., 1958; 7 items
      - No. 6 The influence of neutral facts on values., 1958; 7 items
      - No. 7 Value, biology and physics., 1958; 2 items
      - No. 8. Gestalt psychology and value., 1958; 2 items
      - No. 9. Cognition and value., 1958; 2 items
    - Second course
      - No. 1. A Survey of problems., n.d.; 2 items
      - No. 2. The nature of the organism., n.d.; 1 item
      - No. 3. The physiology of relations., n.d.; 3 items
      - No. 4. Evolution., n.d.; 2 items
      - No. 5. Isomorphism., n.d.; 4 items
      - No. 6. Basic concepts of physics., n.d.; 4 items
      - No. 7. Psychology and neurophysiology., 4 items
      - No. 8. Figural after-effects., n.d.; 2 items
      - No. 9. Currents of the brain., n.d.; 2 items
  - Goethe's color theory, Lecture on, n.d.; 1 item
  - Goethe's Farbenlehre, Lecture on., 1932 June 17; 1 item
  - Has the familiar world a place within the framework of Science? Discussion of cortical currents., n.d.; 1 item
  - Hitchcock Lectures, n.d.
    - No. 1. Psychology and physics., 2 items
    - No. 2. Psychology and Biology, 1 item
      pages 1-6 missing
    - No. 3. Psychological evidence and the brain., 2 items
    - No. 4. A study in brain physics., n.d.; 2 items
  - Humanism and Scientism. A contribution to "Science in the Humanist Tradition," Princeton Bicentennial., 1 item
  - Immigration of European Scientists., n.d.; 1 item
  - Intelligensprufungen am Menschenaffen, 1962; 2 folders
    - Folder 1, 1962; 8 items
    - Folder 2, 1962; 3 items
  - Koyre, Introduction of Prof., n.d.; 1 item
  - Langford Lectures, Princeton, 1966
    - Introduction by Frank Geldard, 1966; 1 item
    - No. 1. Early developments in Gestalt Psychology, 1966; 1 item
    - No. 2. Gestalt Psychology and natural science., 1966; 3 items
    - No. 3. Recent developments in Gestalt Psychology., 1966; 2 items
    - No. 4. What is thinking?, 1966; 3 items
  - Mind-Body problem. Dartmouth, 1959 Oct. 6., 1 item
  - Mind-Body problem (in S. Hook, ed. Dimensions of Mind. New York University Press, 1960.), 3 items
  - Mind-Body problem. Paper read in Ohio., 3 items
  - Movement after-effects and visual after-effects., 1 item
  - The Naturalistic Interpretation of Man (The Trojan Horse)., n.d.; 4 items
  - Obsessions of Normal People., n.d.; 1 item
  - On impartial empiricism., n.d.; 1 item
  - Ontogeny and perception. Princeton University., 2 items
  - Organization in Perception and in Memory, 1960; 1 item
  - Paper on gestalt psychology., n.d.; 1 item
  - Paper to experimentalists, Princeton., n.d.; 2 items
  - Passions., n.d.; 2 items
  - Peace and education., 1 item
  - Perception and attention., 1957; 5 items
  - Perception and neurophysiological models., 3 items
  - Phenomenalistic and Causal-representative theories., 1 item
  - Present situation in brain physiology., n.d.; 5 items
  - Psychologie und Evolutionslehre (Berlin, 1957)., 6 items
  - Psychologie und Hirnphysiologie (Berlin, 1957)., 4 items
  - Psychologie und Naturwissenschaft. Brussels Congress, 1957., 4 items
  - Psychology and Education, given at University of Connecticut., 1 item
  - Psychology and natural science. Incomplete., 2 items
  - Review of J. A. McGeoch, Psychology of Human Learning., 1942; 1 item
  - Science and value., 2 items
  - A Short way from psychology to brain physics. Wellesley College Symposium on the scope of science., n.d.; 2 items
  - Sodhi, Talk at memorial meeting for Kripal., n.d.; 3 items
  - A Strange experience in 1925 (given at Swarthmore College)., n.d.; 2 items
  - Talk at Colby College., n.d.; 1 item
  - Talk at conference on Energy., n.d.; 2 items
  - Talk on insight., n.d.; 2 items
  - Talk to graduating class, Swarthmore, n.d.; 2 folders
    - Folder 1, n.d.; 2 items
    - Folder 2, n.d.; 3 items
  - Task for Gestalt Psychology (received by the APS: Jan. 6, 1970), 1969; 1 item
  - Task for philosophers., 1960; 4 items
  - Television discussion with Asch, 1951; 1 item
  - Time Error in Judgments of Visual Lengths, n.d.; 1 item
  - Unsolved problems in the field of figural after-effects, 1963-1965; 2 folders
    - Folder 1, 1965; 3 items
    - Folder 2, 1963; 4 items
  - Wertheimer (Paper read at the New School?)., n.d.; 2 items
  - Why Psychology? (Swarthmore College)., n.d.; 1 item
  - Wie hat die Einwanderung von Professoren und Ideen aus Europa die Amerikanische Psychologie Beeinfluest?, 1 item
  - Work in brain surgery., n.d.; 2 items
  - Work with chimpanzees., n.d.; 1 item
- Series IV. Manuscripts, Drafts, Notes, 1862-1962; .5 lin. feet (Box 1)
  Manuscripts and drafts of lectures and articles. Includes proofs of "Gespräche in Deutschland"
  - Apes, Old manuscripts and notes on work with, 3 items
  - Discussion of a paper of Mr. Brandt., 1 item
  - Early experiences in America (Notes for talks?)., 1925; 4 items
  - Feigl Festschrift paper, Preliminary notes.., 1961; 6 items
  - Figural after-effects., n.d.; 2 items
  - Figural after-effects in the third dimension of visual space., n.d.; 2 items
  - Gespräche in Deutschland. Proofs., 1 item
  - Gestalt psychology bibliography. (Author unknown), n.d.; 2 items
  - Gestalt Psychology in 1962. Draft., 1 item
  - Gifford lectures manuscripts, n.d.
    - First course, n.d.
      - Lecture I, n.d.; 1 item
      - Lecture II, n.d.; 1 item
      - Lecture III, n.d.; 1 item
      - Lecture IV, n.d.; 1 item
      - Lecture VI, n.d.; 1 item
      - Lecture VII, n.d.; 1 item
      - Lecture VIII and IX, 2 items
    - Second course
      - Lecture I (and draft), 2 items
      - Lecture II (very incomplete), n.d.; 1 item
      - Lecture III, n.d.; 1 item
      - Lecture IV, n.d.; 1 item
      - Lecture V, n.d.; 1 item
      - Lecture VI, n.d.; 1 item
      - Lecture VII, n.d.; 1 item
      - Lecture VIII., n.d.; 1 item
  - La Idea de Sentido y su Valor en la Conducta Humana., 1930; 1 item
  - Isomorphism and brain physiology. (Talk to a philosophical club. Ca. 1951)., 1 item
  - Kant- Vortrage., 1932; 28 items
  - Kenka?, n.d.; 1 item
  - Köhler, Franz. Logik und Encyclopaedie der Philosophie. Prof. Lotze. 1862., 1 item
  - Langfeld lectures, Princeton University, 5 folders
    - Lecture I, n.d.; 1 item
    - Lecture II, n.d.; 1 item
    - Lecture III, n.d.; 1 item
    - Lecture IV, n.d.; 1 item
    - Preliminary Notes, 1966; 3 items
  - Lauenstein material-manuscript, reprint, letters., 1932-1940; 7 items
  - Lecture on thinking, Dartmouth College, ca. 1959., n.d.; 2 items
  - Lectures in Hamburg and Heidelberg, 1954, 1956., 11 items
  - Notes, 1934-1935., 35 items
  - Notes for reply to Lashley., 1951; 7 items
  - Obsessions manuscript. Incomplete., n.d.; 1 item
  - Obsessions of normal people. Incomplete., n.d.; 3 items
  - Philosophie und Naturwissenschaft., 1 item
  - The Place of Value in a World of Facts., n.d.; 4 folders
    German translation with some W. Köhler corrections.
    - Folder 1 (pp. 18-114), n.d.; 1 item
    - Folder 2 (pp. 14-114), n.d.; 1 item
    - Folder 3 (pp. 174-205), n.d.; 2 items
    - Folder 4 (pp. 236-262), n.d.; 1 item
  - Psychological Approach to Problems of Neurology., n.d.; 1 item
  - Psychologie und Naturwissenschaft. International Congress of Psychology. Brussels, 1957. Draft., 1 item
  - Seminar, 1934 Oct. 3, and another manuscript., 4 items
  - Talk on education., n.d.; 1 item
  - Talk on Organization, n.d.; 2 items
  - Task for Philosophers. Notes, outlines, drafts., 1961; 7 items
- Series V. Notes, 1930-1966; .5 lin. feet (Box 1-2)
  Notes from various aspects of Köhler's professional career, including lectures, meetings, and courses (to name a few).
  - Berlin staff., n.d.; 1 item
  - Brain physiology, notes for talk, n.d.; 1 item
  - Brain physiology notes: "The drop-out of molar physics.", n.d.; 1 item
  - British Psychological Society talk...notes., n.d.; 1 item
  - Cortical Currents lecture notes., n.d.; 1 item
  - Das Wesen der Inteligenz, 1930; 1 item
    different from published version
  - Draft of letter commenting on a manuscript or published work., n.d.; 1 item
  - Facilitation (?), 1955; 7 items
  - Feigl (?), 1961; 6 items
  - Figural after-effects., 1960; 4 items
  - Found in Intelligenzprufungen an Anthropoiden., 4 items
  - Gestalt Psychology., n.d.; 1 item
  - Gestalt Psychology notes, etc., n.d.; 4 items
  - Gestalt Psychology-Notes for seminar (at Dartmouth), n.d.; 1 item
  - Gestalt Psychology-Notes for talk in New York, n.d.; 1 item
  - Gestalt Psychology talk notes, n.d.; 1 item
    found in March 1952 Psychological Review
  - Gestalt Psychology today...notes., n.d.; 1 item
  - Gifford Lectures. Notes. First, n.d.; 3 items
  - Gifford Lectures. Notes. Second courses., 3 items
  - Hitchcock lecture and seminar notes., 1 item
  - Hitchcock lecture notes (?), n.d.; 3 items
  - Insight and/or memory notes., 1 item
  - Isolation effect notes., n.d.; 8 items
  - Isolation experiment notes (?), n.d.; 3 items
  - Kelm, Harold, and B.M. Springbett. Figural after-effects study., 1940-1948; 4 items
  - Langfeld lecture notes (?), n.d.; 3 items
  - Lecture notes on evolution of mind-body problem., 1 item
  - Lecture notes on thinking., n.d.; 1 item
  - Lecture on value (?)., n.d.; 1 item
  - Lecture to Parducci's class, based on N.Y. Acad. Lecture: "Electric Currents in the Brain.", n.d.; 1 item
  - Lectures in London and Oslo notes. (Incomplete)., 5 items
  - Mair, Heinrich, On the death of, [and] Letter to Ministeralrat in William James lecture invitation, 1934; 1 item
  - McGee's Seminar lecture notes., n.d.; 2 items
  - Mind-Body notes (?)., 2 items
  - Miscellaneous notes-unidentified, n.d.; 3 folders
    - Folder 1, n.d.; 37 items
    - Folder 2, n.d.; 49 items
    - Folder 3, n.d.; 66 items
  - N.S.F. application. (Notes)., 1959; 1 item
  - Notes, 1959., 7 items
  - Notes as president of the A.P.A., n.d.; 4 items
  - Notes for Gifford lectures, probably., n.d.; 34 items
  - Notes for introduction of A.P.A. officials [and] "Gestalt Psychology Today" (Draft) 1959., 1 item
  - Notes for lecture in Philadelphia and U.C.L.A., 1 item
  - Notes on article by Ivo Köhler in Festschrift [and] Drafts of letters., 1 item
  - Notes on psychological research., n.d.; 2 items
  - Notes on RNA., n.d.; 1 item
  - Notes on the third Dimension., n.d.; 6 items
  - Notes on thinking., n.d.; 3 items
  - Old notes., n.d.; 16 items
  - Old notes. Gestalt u. Gedachtnis?, n.d.; 10 items
  - Perception and attention. Notes to publisher., 1958; 2 items
  - Perception and cortical processes underlying perception. (Notes)., 1 item
  - Perception of velocity notes..., n.d.; 1 item
  - Perception (Notes for talk, perhaps at Dartmouth)., n.d.; 1 item
  - Perceptual organization and learning. Early draft., 1 item
  - Princeton lectures-preliminary notes (?)., 1966; 1 item
  - Principle of Pragnanz, ca. 1951; 1 item